<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> - Articles</title>
    <description>blog.zavrel.net</description>
    <link>
    </link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>When You Hit the Wall</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I strongly believe that the most important skill that makes the difference between the success and the failure is the ability to overcome the phase which will inevitably occur most of the time, especially on long-term projects, hitting the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /another-post-with-cover-image</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/another-post-with-cover-image</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Why the Concept of Evernote Notebooks Is Flawed</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Evernote is an amazing service. I can’t imagine managing all my task and projects without it. I use Evernote regularly for some six years and since I sorted out my methodology and published it as a book and an online course, I can’t fathom how Evernote itself can’t grasp how flawed the concept of notebooks really is.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /why-the-concept-of-evernote-notebooks-is-flawed</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/why-the-concept-of-evernote-notebooks-is-flawed</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Get More Productive with THE SYSTEM2, Now For Free!</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m working with THE SYSTEM2 every single day. I use it to track my personal tasks, my online business projects and even my daily job projects. I can’t even imagine how I could manage all my activities without it.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 22:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /get-more-productive-with-the-system2-now-for-free</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/get-more-productive-with-the-system2-now-for-free</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Talker | Reloaded (Part 2)</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A year ago, I wrote the article about &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.zavrel.net/talker-reloaded-part-1-e817aedd2b49&quot;&gt;Talker&lt;/a&gt;. How it all started and what I plan to do with it next. Well, I’ve realized I wouldn’t reload Talker in a way described in that article. Instead, I will teach how to create Talker from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 23:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /talker-reloaded-part-2</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/talker-reloaded-part-2</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Organising your content with tags</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Ghost has a single, powerful organisational taxonomy, called tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn't matter whether you want to call them categories, tags, boxes, or anything else. You can think of Ghost tags a lot like Gmail labels. By tagging posts with one or more keyword, you can organise articles into buckets of related content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;basictagging&quot;&gt;Basic tagging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you write a post, you can assign tags to help differentiate between categories of content. For example, you might tag some posts with &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt; and other posts with &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt;, which would create two distinct categories of content listed on &lt;code&gt;/tag/news/&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/tag/cycling/&lt;/code&gt;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you tag a post with both &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt; - then it appears in both sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tag archives are like dedicated home-pages for each category of content that you have. They have their own pages, their own RSS feeds, and can support their own cover images and meta data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;theprimarytag&quot;&gt;The primary tag&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside the Ghost editor, you can drag and drop tags into a specific order. The first tag in the list is always given the most importance, and some themes will only display the primary tag (the first tag in the list) by default. So you can add the most important tag which you want to show up in your theme, but also add a bunch of related tags which are less important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;, Cycling, Bart Stevens, Extreme Sports&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, &lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt; is the primary tag which will be displayed by the theme, but the post will also still receive all the other tags, and show up in their respective archives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;privatetags&quot;&gt;Private tags&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you may want to assign a post a specific tag, but you don't necessarily want that tag appearing in the theme or creating an archive page. In Ghost, hashtags are private and can be used for special styling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you sometimes publish posts with video content - you might want your theme to adapt and get rid of the sidebar for these posts, to give more space for an embedded video to fill the screen. In this case, you could use private tags to tell your theme what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;, Cycling, #video&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the theme would assign the post publicly displayed tags of &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt; - but it would also keep a private record of the post being tagged with &lt;code&gt;#video&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your theme, you could then look for private tags conditionally and give them special formatting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;nohighlight&quot;&gt;{{#post}}
    {{#has tag=&amp;quot;#video&amp;quot;}}
        ...markup for a nice big video post layout...
    {{else}}
        ...regular markup for a post...
    {{/has}}
{{/post}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find documentation for theme development techniques like this and many more over on Ghost's extensive &lt;a href=&quot;https://themes.ghost.org/&quot;&gt;theme documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /using-tags</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/using-tags</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
