<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> - Articles</title>
    <description>blog.zavrel.net</description>
    <link>
    </link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>When You Hit the Wall</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I strongly believe that the most important skill that makes the difference between the success and the failure is the ability to overcome the phase which will inevitably occur most of the time, especially on long-term projects, hitting the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /another-post-with-cover-image</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/another-post-with-cover-image</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Why the Concept of Evernote Notebooks Is Flawed</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Evernote is an amazing service. I can’t imagine managing all my task and projects without it. I use Evernote regularly for some six years and since I sorted out my methodology and published it as a book and an online course, I can’t fathom how Evernote itself can’t grasp how flawed the concept of notebooks really is.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /why-the-concept-of-evernote-notebooks-is-flawed</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/why-the-concept-of-evernote-notebooks-is-flawed</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Get More Productive with THE SYSTEM2, Now For Free!</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m working with THE SYSTEM2 every single day. I use it to track my personal tasks, my online business projects and even my daily job projects. I can’t even imagine how I could manage all my activities without it.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 22:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /get-more-productive-with-the-system2-now-for-free</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/get-more-productive-with-the-system2-now-for-free</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Talker | Reloaded (Part 2)</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A year ago, I wrote the article about &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.zavrel.net/talker-reloaded-part-1-e817aedd2b49&quot;&gt;Talker&lt;/a&gt;. How it all started and what I plan to do with it next. Well, I’ve realized I wouldn’t reload Talker in a way described in that article. Instead, I will teach how to create Talker from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 23:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /talker-reloaded-part-2</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/talker-reloaded-part-2</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Resize Images on Mac Like a Pro</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Resizing images is very handy, especially with all those megapixels thrown at us from the latest and greatest smartphones.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 23:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /how-to-resize-images-on-mac-like-a-pro</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/how-to-resize-images-on-mac-like-a-pro</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Tick, Tick, Tick.</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Tick, tick, tick. Every single minute, you have an opportunity to change your life. Sixty times per minute, you have a chance to get up and do something meaningful. How much longer do you plan to waste your time? If you think that tomorrow is fine, you’re wrong. There’s no tomorrow. When tomorrow comes, it will be another today, and you’ll have another 24 hours wasted.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 22:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /tick-tick-tick</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/tick-tick-tick</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
