<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-04-23T18:44:32+00:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">blog.zavrel.net</title><subtitle>blog.zavrel.net</subtitle><entry><title type="html">When You Hit the Wall</title><link href="/another-post-with-cover-image" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When You Hit the Wall" /><published>2018-04-15T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-15T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/another-post-with-cover-image</id><content type="html" xml:base="/another-post-with-cover-image">&lt;p&gt;I strongly believe that the most important skill that makes the difference between the success and the failure is the ability to overcome the phase which will inevitably occur most of the time, especially on long-term projects, hitting the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hitting the wall means getting to the phase when you’re no longer interested in your project, the initial excitement is far gone and all that’s left is the mundane grinding. This is the time when most projects get canceled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who are aware of this phenomenon usually opt for short-term projects so they don’t get to that phase and they try to finish them before the initial excitement get burned out. The risk of this approach lies in the subpar quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think about it, you can’t usually deliver anything substantial in a very short time. You can’t write the book in a day, you can’t record quality online course in a week, you can’t create an amazing mobile game in a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good things just take time to make. The more time you spend on the same project the more probably you are going to hit the wall, but it doesn’t mean that you should abandon long and time-consuming work. It means that you need to understand how to get over the wall and keep going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started producing online content, it was an amazingly painful process, because I was hitting the wall most of the time. I got easily excited, but after few weeks, I just openly hated the whole idea and wanted to drop it. Somehow, I managed to keep going and eventually, the fire got ignited again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It really helps if you just show up. Make your project into a ritual. Don’t think about your emotions when it’s time to sit down and work. Just treat it as something you need to do no matter what. Most of the time, showing up is all it takes. Make an appointment with your project. I mean, really, write it on your calendar, so you can treat it like a meeting. Make a coffee or tea, get ready and go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, you might be able to squeeze only 5 minutes, but even 5 minutes is better than nothing at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, make sure to praise yourself for what you have done. It’s very important to constantly remind yourself that you are making progress, even if it’s very small progress, it will compound over time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jan Zavrel</name></author><category term="productivity" /><summary type="html">I strongly believe that the most important skill that makes the difference between the success and the failure is the ability to overcome the phase which will inevitably occur most of the time, especially on long-term projects, hitting the wall.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why the Concept of Evernote Notebooks Is Flawed</title><link href="/why-the-concept-of-evernote-notebooks-is-flawed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why the Concept of Evernote Notebooks Is Flawed" /><published>2018-04-14T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-14T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/why-the-concept-of-evernote-notebooks-is-flawed</id><content type="html" xml:base="/why-the-concept-of-evernote-notebooks-is-flawed">&lt;p&gt;Evernote is an amazing service. I can’t imagine managing all my task and projects without it. I use Evernote regularly for some six years and since I sorted out my methodology and published it as a book and an online course, I can’t fathom how Evernote itself can’t grasp how flawed the concept of notebooks really is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evernote hides inside its service one of the best implementation of tags available&lt;/strong&gt;, but somehow they haven’t recognized it yet and heavily promote the use of notebooks instead which is beyond my understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Evernote Certified Consultant I pointed out many times during my exam and even within the community of fellow consultants, that &lt;strong&gt;Evernote should really focus on promoting tags instead of notebooks&lt;/strong&gt; because tags offer more versatility compared to somewhat rigid notebooks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evernote-limits&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evernote limits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, notebooks are heavily limited in numbers. Compared to 100.000 tags, you can create only personal 250 notebooks which is ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/why-the-concept-of-evernote-notebooks-is-flawed-img01.png&quot; alt=&quot;Evernote limits&quot; title=&quot;Evernote limits&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;excluding-usage&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Excluding usage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, &lt;strong&gt;notebooks shouldn’t be used as a project storage&lt;/strong&gt;. Not only you are heavily limited, as I mentioned above, but more importantly, you can’t have the same note save in two or more notebooks at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After many years of using Evernote as a project management tool, it happen to me many times that I had to assign one note two three or even more projects, because sometimes, people just tend to send you overviews by emails and they don’t want to send the current progress of each project in separate email. No, they just send it in one email. Now, when you want to store this email in notebooks, which one will you choose? The most important project? The most recent project?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you see how flawed this is. Yet Evernote still suggests that you use notebooks this way while completely ignoring their gold nugget, tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With tags, you don’t have to think about this too long. You can assign 100 tags per note. So if your that overview email mentions 5 projects, you can simply assign 5 tags to this note and you’re done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;proper-naming-convention&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proper naming convention&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I suggest that we should switch from notebooks to tags, the most frequent argument is that with tags, everything would turn into a mess after some time. Yes, if the limit of 250 notebooks makes your Evernote less messy because you can’t simply create more notebooks, that’s fine. With 100.000 tags, you must get into a very messy situation, right? Wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All it takes is a little bit of thinking and a little bit of discipline. With the right naming convention you can keep your list of tags organized even with almost a thousand of them, like in my case:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/why-the-concept-of-evernote-notebooks-is-flawed-img02.png&quot; alt=&quot;Keeping tags organized&quot; title=&quot;Keeping tags organized&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the image above, I have just six notebooks, everything else is managed by tags. Also, I have already almost 6.000 notes in my personal account and yet I am able to find anything almost immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say I need to find that contract signed with that company. Hmm, let’s see. I can easily start searching among all my notes and with just two tags, I’m done: &lt;strong&gt;d.contract&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;k.AUTOCONT&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/why-the-concept-of-evernote-notebooks-is-flawed-img03.png&quot; alt=&quot;Search for anything, super fast!&quot; title=&quot;Search for anything, super fast!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All tags representing &lt;em&gt;document type&lt;/em&gt; start with the &lt;strong&gt;d.&lt;/strong&gt; prefix. You can have d.contract, d.email_sent, d.email_received, d.offer, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All tags representing &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;companies&lt;/em&gt; start with the &lt;strong&gt;k.&lt;/strong&gt; prefix. You can have k.Smith_John, k.MICROSOFT and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, when you search for notes with tags assigned, you don’t have to think about the name of the tag, all you need is to know, that there should always be some &lt;em&gt;document type&lt;/em&gt;, some &lt;em&gt;person&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;company&lt;/em&gt; and ideally even some _project_assigned to the note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, you guessed it. All tags representing project start with the &lt;strong&gt;p.&lt;/strong&gt; prefix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;managing-tasks-withevernote&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Managing tasks with Evernote&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s make it really simple. You should be able to keep track of the progress of your tasks because buying a milk won’t always cut it. Some of the tasks I keep the track of takes more than a year to finish, so without a proper system, I would be completely lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, you can use Evernote as a task manager. Compared to any other alternative, the tags are again the main reason why you shouldn’t consider anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Task are basically notes with a reminder and due date assigned. This way, you can easily sort all your tasks by due date. Active tasks belong to &lt;strong&gt;t.active&lt;/strong&gt;notebook, idle tasks belong to &lt;strong&gt;t.idle&lt;/strong&gt; notebook and completed tasks, well, to &lt;strong&gt;t.completed&lt;/strong&gt; notebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the so-called &lt;em&gt;Arrow Notation&lt;/em&gt;, you can keep track of everything that happens with the particular tasks. &lt;strong&gt;Smith_John -&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; means that Smith gave you some information or asked you to do something while &lt;strong&gt;-&amp;gt; Smith_John&lt;/strong&gt;means that you gave Smith some information or delegated some job to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you bump into somebody at work and by searching for &lt;strong&gt;-&amp;gt; Peter&lt;/strong&gt; you get immediately everything you need to discuss with this poor guy. That’s what I call power and that’s how I am able to manage all of my 129 currently active projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-not-a-coincidence-its-asystem&quot;&gt;It’s not a coincidence, it’s a system&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, this is just a quick sneak peek of the methodology I have invented during my almost 10 years of using Evernote. I call it THE SYSTEM2, because all you need is two types of notebooks, two types of notes and two types of tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THE SYSTEM2 is a book and an online course. It’s based on GTD, but takes it to the next level. It’s Evernote on steroids and it’s available for free of charge for anyone who wants to get the most out of Evernote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;links-youbet&quot;&gt;Links? You bet!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THE SYSTEM2 BOOK: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zavrel.net/the-system2-book.pdf&quot; title=&quot;https://www.zavrel.net/the-system2-book.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.zavrel.net/the-system2-book.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THE SYSTEM2 COURSE: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/evernote-with-the-system2-productivity-gtd-on-steroids&quot; title=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/evernote-with-the-system2-productivity-gtd-on-steroids&quot;&gt;https://www.udemy.com/evernote-with-the-system2-productivity-gtd-on-steroids&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jan Zavrel</name></author><category term="productivity" /><summary type="html">Evernote is an amazing service. I can’t imagine managing all my task and projects without it. I use Evernote regularly for some six years and since I sorted out my methodology and published it as a book and an online course, I can’t fathom how Evernote itself can’t grasp how flawed the concept of notebooks really is.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Get More Productive with THE SYSTEM2, Now For Free!</title><link href="/get-more-productive-with-the-system2-now-for-free" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Get More Productive with THE SYSTEM2, Now For Free!" /><published>2018-04-09T22:00:10+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-09T22:00:10+00:00</updated><id>/get-more-productive-with-the-system2-now-for-free</id><content type="html" xml:base="/get-more-productive-with-the-system2-now-for-free">&lt;p&gt;I’m working with THE SYSTEM2 every single day. I use it to track my personal tasks, my online business projects and even my daily job projects. I can’t even imagine how I could manage all my activities without it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, I wanted to make some money by writing a book about THE SYSTEM2 and also by recording an online course, but yesterday I decided that I wanted everyone who’s interested in getting more productive to have both of these products for free. So from now on, you’ll be able to get my course and the book about THE SYSTEM2 without spending a penny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-thesystem2&quot;&gt;What Is THE SYSTEM2?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THE SYSTEM2 is the name of the methodology for using Evernote. I invented this methodology by combining different approaches, mainly &lt;a href=&quot;https://gettingthingsdone.com/&quot;&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/a&gt; (GTD) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://thesecretweapon.org/&quot;&gt;The Secret Weapon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate using multiple tools. I like things simple. That’s why I’ve always wanted one place for everything and Evernote gave me this except for the proper task management. The power of Evernote, though, is in its freedom of use, so I invented my own way to use it as a task manager and document storage at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;two-types-ofnotes&quot;&gt;Two types of notes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simplicity and power. THE SYSTEM2 brings both at the same time. You will work with just two types of notes. Reference notes and task notes. That’s all you’ll ever need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;two-types-of-notebooks&quot;&gt;Two types of notebooks&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A notebook isn’t the ideal tool for organizing stuff. That’s why you need to limit the number of notebooks to the minimum. You will work with just two types of notebooks. One for storing reference notes and one for storing task notes. Yes, it’s that simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;two-type-oftags&quot;&gt;Two type of tags&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags are the real power behind THE SYSTEM2. You will use two types of tags. Reference tags and task tags with Arrow Notation to further optimize your workflow. This tagging system will help you find anything, super fast!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;two-types-ofroles&quot;&gt;Two types of roles&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A truly powerful productivity system needs to work as a task manager and a storage for reference materials at the same time. With THE SYSTEM2, you’ll get exactly this, because it combines the two roles efficiently and flawlessly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-should-you-use-thesystem2&quot;&gt;Why Should You Use THE SYSTEM2?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy. If you want to be productive, if you want to do more in less time, or simply if you want to be able to keep track of every single task or project you need to work on or manage, I believe you will hardly find anything better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this statement is pretty bold. But I have yet to find something that will make me leave THE SYSTEM2. I am constantly searching for more optimization, so if there’s better product or methodology, I will happily use it instead of THE SYSTEM2, but there is not or I don’t know about it yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-should-you-believeme&quot;&gt;Why Should You Believe Me?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For two reason. First, I’ve been using this system for many years. I know it in and out and since I invented it, I can help you with your first steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, I kind of know Evernote, because I am one of Evernote Certified Consultants, so there’s some credit backed by Evernote itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-can-you-get-thesystem2&quot;&gt;Where Can You Get THE SYSTEM2?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to Udemy.com and just enroll in my course: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/evernote-with-the-system2-productivity-gtd-on-steroids/&quot; title=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/evernote-with-the-system2-productivity-gtd-on-steroids/&quot;&gt;https://www.udemy.com/evernote-with-the-system2-productivity-gtd-on-steroids/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jan Zavrel</name></author><category term="productivity" /><summary type="html">I’m working with THE SYSTEM2 every single day. I use it to track my personal tasks, my online business projects and even my daily job projects. I can’t even imagine how I could manage all my activities without it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Talker | Reloaded (Part 2)</title><link href="/talker-reloaded-part-2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Talker | Reloaded (Part 2)" /><published>2018-03-19T23:00:39+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-19T23:00:39+00:00</updated><id>/talker-reloaded-part-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/talker-reloaded-part-2">&lt;p&gt;A year ago, I wrote the article about &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.zavrel.net/talker-reloaded-part-1-e817aedd2b49&quot;&gt;Talker&lt;/a&gt;. How it all started and what I plan to do with it next. Well, I’ve realized I wouldn’t reload Talker in a way described in that article. Instead, I will teach how to create Talker from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;meet-my-newcourse&quot;&gt;Meet my new course&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently working on a new course focused on full-stack web development. A few months ago I finished the script which has over 127.000 words and now I’m in the middle of the production of the course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course is aimed for total beginners who have no previous experience with web development. My goal is to teach them everything they need to know so they can start working on their own web applications once they finish this course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the course, I’ll explain both the front-end and back-end technologies. I will cover HTML, CSS, and Javascript, but also PHP and MySQL. I will discuss different development environments like Docker, Vagrant or XAMPP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once students acquire the basic knowledge of these technologies, we will move together to the fun part. We will start building Talker from scratch. Step by step, we will create a database-driven web application with the logic coded in PHP. We will use Bootstrap to make the whole application mobile-ready and responsive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;take-a-sneakpeek&quot;&gt;Take a sneak peek&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, here are some images of what you can expect. I hope you’ll join me as a student once the course is ready!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/talker-reloaded-part2-img01.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/talker-reloaded-part2-img02.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/talker-reloaded-part2-img03.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/talker-reloaded-part2-img04.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jan Zavrel</name></author><category term="web development" /><summary type="html">A year ago, I wrote the article about Talker. How it all started and what I plan to do with it next. Well, I’ve realized I wouldn’t reload Talker in a way described in that article. Instead, I will teach how to create Talker from scratch.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Organising your content with tags</title><link href="/using-tags" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Organising your content with tags" /><published>2017-07-27T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/using-tags</id><content type="html" xml:base="/using-tags">&lt;p&gt;Ghost has a single, powerful organisational taxonomy, called tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn't matter whether you want to call them categories, tags, boxes, or anything else. You can think of Ghost tags a lot like Gmail labels. By tagging posts with one or more keyword, you can organise articles into buckets of related content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;basictagging&quot;&gt;Basic tagging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you write a post, you can assign tags to help differentiate between categories of content. For example, you might tag some posts with &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt; and other posts with &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt;, which would create two distinct categories of content listed on &lt;code&gt;/tag/news/&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/tag/cycling/&lt;/code&gt;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you tag a post with both &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt; - then it appears in both sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tag archives are like dedicated home-pages for each category of content that you have. They have their own pages, their own RSS feeds, and can support their own cover images and meta data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;theprimarytag&quot;&gt;The primary tag&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside the Ghost editor, you can drag and drop tags into a specific order. The first tag in the list is always given the most importance, and some themes will only display the primary tag (the first tag in the list) by default. So you can add the most important tag which you want to show up in your theme, but also add a bunch of related tags which are less important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;, Cycling, Bart Stevens, Extreme Sports&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, &lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt; is the primary tag which will be displayed by the theme, but the post will also still receive all the other tags, and show up in their respective archives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;privatetags&quot;&gt;Private tags&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you may want to assign a post a specific tag, but you don't necessarily want that tag appearing in the theme or creating an archive page. In Ghost, hashtags are private and can be used for special styling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you sometimes publish posts with video content - you might want your theme to adapt and get rid of the sidebar for these posts, to give more space for an embedded video to fill the screen. In this case, you could use private tags to tell your theme what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;, Cycling, #video&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the theme would assign the post publicly displayed tags of &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt; - but it would also keep a private record of the post being tagged with &lt;code&gt;#video&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your theme, you could then look for private tags conditionally and give them special formatting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;nohighlight&quot;&gt;{{#post}}
    {{#has tag=&amp;quot;#video&amp;quot;}}
        ...markup for a nice big video post layout...
    {{else}}
        ...regular markup for a post...
    {{/has}}
{{/post}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find documentation for theme development techniques like this and many more over on Ghost's extensive &lt;a href=&quot;https://themes.ghost.org/&quot;&gt;theme documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ghost</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">Ghost has a single, powerful organisational taxonomy, called tags. It doesn't matter whether you want to call them categories, tags, boxes, or anything else. You can think of Ghost tags a lot like Gmail labels. By tagging posts with one or more keyword, you can organise articles into buckets of related content. Basic tagging When you write a post, you can assign tags to help differentiate between categories of content. For example, you might tag some posts with News and other posts with Cycling, which would create two distinct categories of content listed on /tag/news/ and /tag/cycling/, respectively. If you tag a post with both News and Cycling - then it appears in both sections. Tag archives are like dedicated home-pages for each category of content that you have. They have their own pages, their own RSS feeds, and can support their own cover images and meta data. The primary tag Inside the Ghost editor, you can drag and drop tags into a specific order. The first tag in the list is always given the most importance, and some themes will only display the primary tag (the first tag in the list) by default. So you can add the most important tag which you want to show up in your theme, but also add a bunch of related tags which are less important. News, Cycling, Bart Stevens, Extreme Sports In this example, News is the primary tag which will be displayed by the theme, but the post will also still receive all the other tags, and show up in their respective archives. Private tags Sometimes you may want to assign a post a specific tag, but you don't necessarily want that tag appearing in the theme or creating an archive page. In Ghost, hashtags are private and can be used for special styling. For example, if you sometimes publish posts with video content - you might want your theme to adapt and get rid of the sidebar for these posts, to give more space for an embedded video to fill the screen. In this case, you could use private tags to tell your theme what to do. News, Cycling, #video Here, the theme would assign the post publicly displayed tags of News, and Cycling - but it would also keep a private record of the post being tagged with #video. In your theme, you could then look for private tags conditionally and give them special formatting: {{#post}} {{#has tag=&amp;quot;#video&amp;quot;}} ...markup for a nice big video post layout... {{else}} ...regular markup for a post... {{/has}} {{/post}} You can find documentation for theme development techniques like this and many more over on Ghost's extensive theme documentation.</summary></entry></feed>